[
	{"id":0,"question":"What sort of ruler did the Israelites ask Samuel to appoint for them?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"A king"},{"id":2,"text":"A judge"},{"id":3,"text":"A prophet"},{"id":3,"text":"A warrior"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"A king (1 Samuel 8:5)"}]},
	{"id":1,"question":"I once dreamd of a lader going to heaven?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Jacob"},{"id":2,"text":"Adam"},{"id":3,"text":"Esaw"},{"id":3,"text":"Seth"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Jacob (Genesis 25:19)"}]},
	{"id":2,"question":"My wife got turned to salt looking at a burning city?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Lot"},{"id":2,"text":"Samuel"},{"id":3,"text":"Adam"},{"id":3,"text":"Samsun"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Lot (Genisis 19:26)"}]},
	{"id":3,"question":"How old did Methuselah live?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"969"},{"id":2,"text":"978"},{"id":3,"text":"920"},{"id":3,"text":"696"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"969 (Genesis)"}]},
	{"id":4,"question":"Ravens brought food to which Old Testament prophet?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Elijah"},{"id":2,"text":"Isaiah"},{"id":3,"text":"Jeremiah"},{"id":3,"text":"Elisha"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Elijah (1 Kings 17:1-7)"}]},
	{"id":5,"question":"Who was Cain's first son?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Enoch"},{"id":2,"text":"Irad"},{"id":3,"text":"Mehujael"},{"id":3,"text":"Lamech"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Enoch (Genesis 4:17)"}]},
	{"id":6,"question":"Which prophet saw God give life to a pile of dry bones?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Ezekiel"},{"id":2,"text":"Hosea"},{"id":3,"text":"Haggai"},{"id":3,"text":"Zechariah"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Ezekiel (Ezekiel 37)"}]},
	{"id":7,"question":"At the time of the census conducted by Moses in the first chapter of Numbers, which of the twelve tribes of Israel was the smallest?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Manasseh"},{"id":2,"text":"Joseph"},{"id":3,"text":"Zebulun"},{"id":3,"text":"Issachar"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Manasseh (Numbers 1:34)"}]},
	{"id":8,"question":"What is the name of the second book in the Old Testament?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Exodus"},{"id":2,"text":"Leviticus"},{"id":3,"text":"Genesis"},{"id":3,"text":"Deuteronomy"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Exodus (The Bible)"}]},
	{"id":9,"question":"The name of God is not mentioned in only one book of the Bible. Which one is it?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Esther"},{"id":2,"text":"Obadiah"},{"id":3,"text":"Jude"},{"id":3,"text":"Ruth"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Esther (Esther 1-9)"}]},
	{"id":10,"question":"On which day did God create animals?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Sixth day"},{"id":2,"text":"Fourth day"},{"id":3,"text":"Third day"},{"id":3,"text":"Fifth day"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Sixth day (Genesis 1:24-31)"}]},
	{"id":11,"question":"Who built the first altar in the Bible?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Noah"},{"id":2,"text":"Abraham"},{"id":3,"text":"Adam"},{"id":3,"text":"Cain"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Noah (Genesis 8:20)"}]},
	{"id":12,"question":"How long did Jacob work for Laban in order to marry Rachel?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"14 years"},{"id":2,"text":"7 years"},{"id":3,"text":"12 years"},{"id":3,"text":"7 months"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"14 (Genesis 29:20&27)"}]},
	{"id":13,"question":"Who ate honey out of a lion's carcass?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Samson"},{"id":2,"text":"Goliath"},{"id":3,"text":"King Saul"},{"id":3,"text":"King David"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Samson (Judges 14:5-9)"}]},
	{"id":14,"question":"Which famous city did Nebuchadnezzar rule?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Babylon"},{"id":2,"text":"Nineveh"},{"id":3,"text":"Jericho"},{"id":3,"text":"Damascus"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Babylon (Daniel 1:1)"}]},
	{"id":15,"question":"Who was Israel's first high priest?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Aaron"},{"id":2,"text":"Eli"},{"id":3,"text":"Phinehas"},{"id":3,"text":"Eleazar"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Aaron (Exodus 28)"}]},
	{"id":16,"question":"Who were the parents of King Solomon?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"David and Bathsheba"},{"id":2,"text":"David and Michal"},{"id":3,"text":"David and Abigail"},{"id":3,"text":"David and Maachah"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"David and Bathsheba (2 Samuel 12:24)"}]},
	{"id":17,"question":"In the Bible, who did the sun and moon stand still before?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Joshua"},{"id":2,"text":"Moses"},{"id":3,"text":"King David"},{"id":3,"text":"Gideon"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Joshua (Joshua 10:13)"}]},
	{"id":18,"question":"Who is the only woman whose age is mentioned in the Bible?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Sarah"},{"id":2,"text":"Deborah"},{"id":3,"text":"Mary"},{"id":3,"text":"Esther"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Sarah (Genesis 17:17)"}]},
	{"id":19,"question":"Who did Mordecai refuse to bow down to?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Haman"},{"id":2,"text":"Nebuchadnezzar"},{"id":3,"text":"King Ahab"},{"id":3,"text":"Pontius Pilate"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Haman (Esther 3:5)"}]},
	{"id":20,"question":"What kind of wood was used to make Noah's Ark?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Gopher wood"},{"id":2,"text":"Acacia wood"},{"id":3,"text":"Cedar wood"},{"id":3,"text":"Sycamore wood"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Gopher wood - Genesis 6:14 (Genesis 6:14)"}]},
	{"id":21,"question":"How old was Moses when he died?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"120"},{"id":2,"text":"110"},{"id":3,"text":"90"},{"id":3,"text":"100"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"120 (Deuteronomy 34:7)"}]},
	{"id":22,"question":"Which animal is mentioned most frequently in the Bible?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Sheep"},{"id":2,"text":"Bullock"},{"id":3,"text":"Horses"},{"id":3,"text":"Lions"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Sheep"}]},
	{"id":23,"question":"Who was given a coat of many colors?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Joseph"},{"id":2,"text":"Simeon"},{"id":3,"text":"Daniel"},{"id":3,"text":"Lydia of Thyatira"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Joseph (Genesis 37:3)"}]},
	{"id":24,"question":"What weapons did the Philistine giant, Goliath carry when he was slain by David?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"A sword and a spear"},{"id":2,"text":"A spear and a bow"},{"id":3,"text":"A knife and a sword"},{"id":3,"text":"A sling and a sword"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"A sword and a spear - 1 Samuel 17:45 (1 Samuel 17:45)"}]},
	{"id":25,"question":"From which part of Adam's body did God create Eve?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Rib"},{"id":2,"text":"Head"},{"id":3,"text":"Knee"},{"id":3,"text":"Foot"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Rib (Genesis 2:18\u201322)"}]},
	{"id":26,"question":"What was the first bird that Noah let out of the ark?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Raven"},{"id":2,"text":"Dove"},{"id":3,"text":"Duck"},{"id":3,"text":"Eagle"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Raven (Genesis 8:7)"}]},
	{"id":27,"question":"What was the name of Abraham's nephew?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Lot"},{"id":2,"text":"Isaac"},{"id":3,"text":"Haran"},{"id":3,"text":"Ishmael"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Lot (Genesis 14:12)"}]},
	{"id":28,"question":"What did God ask Abraham to sacrifice to him on Mount Moriah?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"His only son"},{"id":2,"text":"A ram"},{"id":3,"text":"A turtledove"},{"id":3,"text":"His wife"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"His only son (Genesis 22:2)"}]},
	{"id":29,"question":"What did Rachel steal from her father, Laban, when she left home with her husband Jacob?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Laban's household gods"},{"id":2,"text":"Laban's money"},{"id":3,"text":"Laban's household jewels"},{"id":3,"text":"Laban's favourite camel"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Laban's household gods (Genesis 31:34)"}]},
	{"id":30,"question":"What was the name of Joseph's youngest brother?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Benjamin"},{"id":2,"text":"Manasseh"},{"id":3,"text":"Asher"},{"id":3,"text":"David"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Benjamin (Genesis 43:29)"}]},
	{"id":31,"question":"When Joseph was in prison, whose dream did he correctly interpret to mean he would be restored to his job?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Cupbearer"},{"id":2,"text":"Baker"},{"id":3,"text":"Head Chef"},{"id":3,"text":"Chief Magician"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Cupbearer (Genesis 40:21)"}]},
	{"id":32,"question":"What was baby Moses hidden in?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"A basket made of bulrushes"},{"id":2,"text":"A large water pot"},{"id":3,"text":"An animal skin bag"},{"id":3,"text":"A bread basket"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"A basket made of bulrushes (Exodus 2:3)"}]},
	{"id":33,"question":"How did Rahab let the invading Israelites identify her house?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"She tied a red rope in her window"},{"id":2,"text":"She painted the door red"},{"id":3,"text":"She put a red flag on the roof"},{"id":3,"text":"She left a red bowl by the front door"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"She tied a red rope in her window (Joshua 2:18)"}]},
	{"id":34,"question":"What weapons did Gideon use to defeat the Midianites?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Trumpets, pitchers and lamps"},{"id":2,"text":"Swords and shields"},{"id":3,"text":"Spears"},{"id":3,"text":"The ark of God and flaming torches"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Trumpets, pitchers and lamps (Judges 7:20)"}]},
	{"id":35,"question":"Which judge was betrayed to the Philistines by a woman?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Samson"},{"id":2,"text":"Joshua"},{"id":3,"text":"Jephthah"},{"id":3,"text":"Barak"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Samson (Judges 16:5)"}]},
	{"id":36,"question":"Who did Samuel anoint as the first King of Israel?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Saul"},{"id":2,"text":"David"},{"id":3,"text":"Jonathan"},{"id":3,"text":"Joshua"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Saul (1 Samuel 10:1)"}]},
	{"id":37,"question":"What did king Solomon ask for from God?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Wisdom"},{"id":2,"text":"Money"},{"id":3,"text":"Power"},{"id":3,"text":"A long life"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Wisdom (1 Kings 3:9)"}]},
	{"id":38,"question":"Who wrote this line \"The Lord is my Shepherd, I shall not want\"?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"King David"},{"id":2,"text":"King Solomon"},{"id":3,"text":"Aspah"},{"id":3,"text":"Moses"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"King David (Psalm 23)"}]},
	{"id":29,"question":"Who was the mother of Samuel?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Hannah"},{"id":2,"text":"Rachel"},{"id":3,"text":"Deborah"},{"id":3,"text":"Michal"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Hannah (1 Samuel 1)"}]},
	{"id":40,"question":"When was blood applied to the ear, thumb and toe by the priest?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Day of cleansing for lepers"},{"id":2,"text":"The Passover"},{"id":3,"text":"Day of Atonement"},{"id":3,"text":"Feast of Tabernacles"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Day of cleansing for lepers (Leviticus 14:14)"}]},
	{"id":41,"question":"What kind of bird brought Elijah food while he hid in the Kerith Ravine, east of Jordan?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Ravens"},{"id":2,"text":"Quail"},{"id":3,"text":"Eagles"},{"id":3,"text":"Doves"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Ravens (1 Kings 17:2-16)"}]},
	{"id":42,"question":"What is the last word in the Old Testament?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Curse"},{"id":2,"text":"Lord"},{"id":3,"text":"Hosts"},{"id":3,"text":"Day"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Curse (Malachi 4:6)"}]},
	{"id":43,"question":"Who was Ruth's son?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Obed"},{"id":2,"text":"Jesse"},{"id":3,"text":"David"},{"id":3,"text":"Boaz"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Obed (Ruth 4:17)"}]},
	{"id":44,"question":"What were the tabernacle candlesticks made of?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"Gold"},{"id":2,"text":"Silver"},{"id":3,"text":"Brass"},{"id":3,"text":"Bronze"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"Gold (Exo 25:31)"}]},
	{"id":45,"question":"How many men did Gideon end up taking to fight the Midionites, as the Lord directed?","choices":[{"id":1,"text":"300"},{"id":2,"text":"3,000"},{"id":3,"text":"30"},{"id":3,"text":"30,000"}],"answer":[{"id":1,"explanation":"300 - The 300 men were used by God to conquer the Midianites. (Judges 7:7)"}]}
]